Your Highness, are you
over the moon right now?
I want to hold it back,
but I just can't.
You said I am the best,
and that you would marry no one but me.
Your Highness,
didn't we agree long ago
that this marriage
is mutually beneficial?
Don't tell me
you mistakenly thought what I said
was genuinely from my heart?
Why can't you just humor me a bit?
I am very easy to please.
=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 13=
Your Highness, you personally
escorted me back to my manor.
Four hours
have already passed since then.
When are you leaving?
Four hours already?
Time flies so fast.
What are we having for dinner?
When did I ever invite you
to have dinner with me, Your Highness?
It's just the way to treat a guest.
I thought you would understand that.
Do you even have
the awareness of being a guest?
So you also feel that I am more like
the master of the house?
You'd better just stay hungry.
Since you don't want to see me,
I'll just leave.
I'll come to see you another day.
No need to see me out.
Why does it feel like
Crown Prince is
acting a bit strange today?
Where is my handkerchief?
Wasn't it just right here?
A Crown Prince
actually turned into
a thief for a handkerchief?
Who would believe this if it got out?
Would you believe it?
Your Highness,
ever since you came back from
Commandery Princess's place,
you've been in
a constant state of excitement.
Your eyes are as bright
as the morning star.
I don't even dare to
look at you directly.
Tian Yuan,
I...
discovered a secret of Xihe's.
Look.
Immortal Vine
is embroidered on this handkerchief?
It really is the Immortal Vine.
Tell me,
Commandery Princess embroidered
the Immortal Vine on her handkerchief.
What does this mean?
I don't know the answer.
Although she seems cold on the surface,
she actually values
old bonds very much in her heart.
This Immortal Vine once
helped her out of a tight spot,
so she never forgot it.
If she treats a mere herb like this,
then what about a person
who stays by her side every day
and shares both joys
and sorrows with her?
Commandery Princess's thoughts
are very hard for
ordinary people to guess.
Moreover,
many people trust objects
more than they trust human hearts.
Wait. Commandery Princess doesn't know
that you were the one
who gave her the Immortal Vine.
So, why would she give
this handkerchief to you?
You didn't steal
the handkerchief, did you?
It's getting late.
Go prepare for the Jiuxiao
Lantern Festival in a few days.
There must not be the slightest mistake.
Understood.
You should also rest early,
Your Highness.
What a child.
(Qingfeng House)
Sir, come on in.
- Xihe.
- Inside, please.
The shad soup
in this restaurant is delicious.
I especially told them
to save a large one.
Later on,
let's have drinks together.
Why are you playing
the attentive host so much today?
It's all because you
are about to marry
the Crown Prince soon.
My heart is broken and grieved.
I was thinking
that before you enter the palace,
every extra day I can spend with you
is a day to cherish.
You don't need to be heartbroken.
Without me, you can always
go find Vice Minitser Cui.
I don't even need to
marry Princess Anling anymore.
Why should I keep looking for him?
Well, I feel
that in the way he looks at you,
there is a great deal of affection.
What do you mean by that?
Don't scare me.
Although he acts disgusted verbally,
he often appears
by your side on purpose.
Can't you feel it at all?
Usually, it's me pestering him,
and he wishes nothing more
than to stay far away from me.
Vice Minitser Cui.
Your Highness.
Young Master Bu.
I'm suddenly not hungry anymore.
Let's go look around
and come back to eat later. Let's go.
(Imperial Guard)
Get me a roast goose tonight.
Yes, sir.
I forgot the case files.
Captain,
which case files are you talking about?
We brought them all.
Shut up.
(Imperial Guard)
Stop right there.
Why have you been avoiding me lately?
Vice Minitser Cui,
my superior is waiting
for me to report on the case.
Excuse me.
Captain Bu.
Wait,
what is wrong with you?
Curfew is about to start in the palace.
What are you still standing here for?
I just wanted to ask you
why you are avoiding me.
My pestering you every day in the past
was making trouble out of nothing.
But rest assured,
from now on,
even if I run into you on the street,
I will treat you like a stranger.
I was wrong before, alright?
Please don't take it to heart.
From now on,
I'll watch my words and actions
and draw a clear line between us.
Cut ties.
Yes, cut ties.
You pester me whenever you want,
and cut ties whenever you please.
Why are you so willful?
Fine.
Let's make things clear today.
I won't pester you anymore,
and you don't pester me either.
Young Master Bu still
refuses to acknowledge you?
Did you say something hurtful?
Tomorrow
is the Jiuxiao Lantern Festival.
After the festival,
I'll marry Commandery Princess.
Don't wear
that half-dead look on your face.
You should look full of joy.
He wants to cut ties with me
and told me not to look for him again.
Is that why
you've been so unhappy?
I just find it baffling.
In the past, when he pestered me,
I was utterly annoyed.
But now that he suddenly walks away,
I actually feel suffocated with anger.
I'm angry at myself
for caring about him this much.
You must have lost your heart to him.
Your Highness...
You didn't mishear.
Precisely because
you've lost your heart to him,
you feel this way.
Please don't joke, Your Highness.
He...
He is a young man.
What if she isn't a man?
Young Master Bu came
to the capital as a child.
So many people know him.
How...
How could this
be possible?
I've said enough.
If you want to know the answer,
find a way yourself.
(Jiuxiao Lantern Festival)
How incredible!
Cloud Moon Cake,
Plum Shadow Curd,
and Snow Milk Balls.
These are all
festive snacks for the festival.
Try them.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Usually,
I see you eat with great restraint.
No matter how much you like something,
you stop after just a few bites.
When you eat with me in the future,
there is no need to be so particular.
Eat as much as you want.
A jade hairpin
signifies a proposal to a primary wife.
As the wind blows, the flowers bloom.
Just like my heart for you,
they are the wind and flowers
that never miss their time.
No matter how the years go by,
I will never fail you.
♪A wall that collapses at a single push♪
♪Frost that melts at a single smile♪
♪How can you be this wonderful♪
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower
that withers after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
Xihe,
for as long as I can remember,
my heart
has never been this joyful.
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
I will strive to be a good wife to you,
and a good Crown Princess.
♪Give you a moon in return♪
But toward Your Highness,
I still have no romantic feelings.
I know
that saying this now
might seem like a mood killer,
but I prefer to make everything clear.
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
I have always liked your honesty.
You only need to remember our agreement.
If one day
you fall for me,
you must tell me right away.
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
Look over there.
♪Amidst the flickering lights♪
♪Alone for several autumns♪
♪How to choose the one♪
♪To be with forever?♪
♪When I gaze upon you♪
♪Flower petals twirl gently in my heart♪
♪Gracefully♪
♪For all eternity♪
♪The timeless wind and moon♪
♪Quietly reflect in your sparkling eyes♪
♪Scattered red petals fall like rain♪
♪It's a wonderful time in the world♪
Did Your Highness paint
the painting on
the lantern shade yourself?
Yes.
It depicts you and me
and...
what our child would look like.
♪I once said all
my goodbyes in a past life♪
My promise to you
is made with the whole world as witness.
♪I will hold you in this lifetime
until the very end♪
My heart for you
will never change.
♪And a pool of me♪
Xihe,
sleep well tonight.
Let's go.
Tian Yuan,
go protect the Commandery Princess.
Commandery Princess.
Go protect the Crown Prince now.
His Highness ordered me to protect you.
Go now!
We must not let you
come to the slightest harm.
Forgive me,
but I cannot leave your side.
Commandery Princess,
you can't go over there.
It's too dangerous here.
Please go back now, Commandery Princess.
The person who just
passed by was Princess Ding,
Li Yanhui?
Princess Ding was the princess
of the former Nanzhou State.
Are there still subordinates
loyal to her by her side?
Since Nanzhou surrendered,
its people have become
citizens of our Daxing.
However, there are some people
who only take orders from Li Yanhui.
Does Your Highness think
this assassination attempt
is related to Princess Ding?
Today is the national
memorial day of Nanzhou.
Li Yanhui went out
with her face covered,
likely to quietly pay respects
to her former homeland.
(Clarity and Serenity)
Your Highness,
during the search,
the Palace Guard found Prince Ding's
Consort, Li Yanhui, by the river.
They asked why
she was there late at night,
but she remained silent.
Just as they were in a bind,
Prince Ding arrived to vouch for her
and insisted on taking her away.
The riverside is a place
for memorial rituals.
It seems your suspicion
was correct, Your Highness.
Li Yanhui traveled masked at night
to pay tribute to her former homeland.
Oh,
she was bundled up tonight.
How did you determine right away
that she was Li Yanhui?
The scent I noticed on Li Yanhui
is identical
to the incense Prince Ding uses.
But you have only met them
once.
Once is enough.
Even with the same ingredients,
if the ratio differs,
I can still detect it.
Last time, at Prince Ding's manor,
I noticed the incense Prince Ding used
was "Four Rejections Incense".
That is usually favored by poor scholars
to show their elegant
contentment with poverty.
The scent is faint.
Yet Prince Ding
carefully blended top-tier ingredients.
This formula must be his own creation.
I could not have mistaken it.
Your sense of smell is extraordinary.
You are uniquely gifted.
Your Highness, what is wrong?
I never understood
how Commandery Princess
saw through my disguise so quickly.
I wanted to know,
if someone impersonates an official,
what would the punishment be?
Now,
I finally understand.
Every time before
I disguised myself to see her,
I would take a pill
containing Tagara Incense
to alter my voice.
She recognized it based on the scent
of Tagara Incense.
The scent is very faint.
Normal people cannot detect it.
But the Commandery Princess can.
The ratio of this Tagara Incense formula
was custom-blended for me by the abbot
when I was at the Taoist temple.
It is the only one.
Normally,
I wear Father's sachet,
which has a very strong herbal scent.
So it masked
the lingering scent of Tagara Incense,
preventing her from recognizing me.
Your Highness,
among those gifts you sent
to the Commandery Princess,
one of them
is a pair of Tagara Incense bracelets.
She has not seen them yet.
If she sees it,
she will know that I am the one
with the Tagara incense.
She will also understand
my strategy in court,
and she will understand
that I am not the man she thinks I am,
a Crown Prince with no backing.
Your Highness.
Quick! Summon
the Chief Imperial Physician!
Your Highness.
Your Highness!
Crown Prince's cold toxin is flaring up.
Prepare the medicinal bath.
- Yes, sir.
Quick. Move faster, everyone.
- Greetings, Your Majesty.
Rise.
How is the Crown Prince?
Replying to Your Majesty,
the toxin in his body
is already hardest
to suppress in winter.
Today, a sudden surge
of severe anxiety and anger
caused the toxin
to spiral out of control.
Tian Yuan,
why did the Crown Prince suffer such
a sudden surge of anxiety and anger?
I do not know either.
It is my incompetence
for failing to take
proper care of Crown Prince.
Please punish me, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
the Crown Prince needs a medicinal bath,
followed by acupuncture
to clear his acupoints,
before his condition
can be temporarily eased.
Only...
Only what?
The risk is very high.
A single mistake
could lead to...
I have only
a 30 percent chance of success.
Thirty percent?
Is there really no other way?
The poison flared up
too violently this time.
If we don't administer
acupuncture immediately,
I'm afraid he might...
Your Majesty,
let them treat him.
At a time like this,
we can't afford to hesitate anymore.
Any further delay,
and I'm afraid Huayong
will be in grave danger.
What are you still standing there for?
Go treat him now.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
Xihe,
given Huayong's current condition,
are you
still willing to marry
into the East Palace?
Your father entrusted you to us.
If you want to back out now,
we would never blame you.
Your Majesty,
Grand Empress Dowager,
husband and wife are one,
for better or worse.
If I were the one lying
on the sickbed right now,
I wouldn't want
my husband to abandon me either.
The Crown Prince
and I share a bond of hearts.
My mind is made up.
To have such character and grace,
you are worthy of
being the Crown Princess.
I shall take my leave.
Youyou...
I'm here.
What did you want to say?
Why are your hands so cold?
Go build up the charcoal fire.
Move it closer.
Yes.
And bring another blanket.
How can they still be this cold?
All of you may leave us.
- Yes.
Youyou...
I'm here.
Youyou,
there are things I want to tell you.
You don't need to say anything.
Just focus on getting better.
Your Majesties,
after the acupuncture,
the toxin inside the Crown Prince's
body has been suppressed.
Once he wakes up,
he will be out of danger.
Wonderful.
I will be waiting outside the hall.
Zhaoning,
you've been looking after
Huayong day and night without rest.
It's been hard on you.
Commandery Princess Zhaoning,
now you can finally
put your mind at ease.
Go back and get some rest early.
Thank you for your concern,
Your Majesties.
I will come to visit
the Crown Prince again tomorrow.
If you keep pushing yourself
and fall ill as well,
what are we to do then?
The Crown Prince's
cold toxin has been suppressed.
We don't need to stay up
keeping watch anymore.
The bed has already been scented.
Please go and get a good night's sleep.
I'm not tired yet.
There's one thing
I haven't been able to figure out.
Right after I left the East Palace,
the Crown Prince had his relapse.
When His Majesty asked about it,
Tian Yuan cast a glance at me.
Could it be
that Crown Prince's
sudden surge of anxiety and anger
actually had something to do with me?
And these past few days,
whenever Tian Yuan sees me,
he acts so strangely.
The Crown Prince's
health has always fluctuated.
Please don't worry too much,
Your Highness.
Your Highness,
the Grand Minister of Rites
has arrived with
the imperial decree for your marriage.
By the grace of Heaven,
a union is ordained.
The Crown Prince is of
noble character and supreme virtue.
As he has come of age,
the East Palace needs a mistress.
Shen Xihe, the eldest daughter
of Duke of Wei, Shen Yueshan,
comes from an illustrious family
and possesses all four virtues.
She is hereby betrothed
to the Crown Prince.
By Imperial Order.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I accept the decree.
Congratulations, Your Highness.
I must return to the palace to report.
I'll visit another day
to offer my congratulations.
Thank you for your trouble,
Minister Zhang.
Mo Yu, see our guest out.
These are the betrothal gifts
from the Crown Prince.
Would you like to examine them,
Your Highness?
Bring them all in.
Yes, Your Highness.
Your Highness,
you're finally awake.
Have you gotten back
the pair of bracelets
I gave the Commandery Princess
as her betrothal gift?
It is already too late.
What do you mean?
Commandery Princess,
there are 20 pieces of jade here.
I only brought a few chests
for you to look at first.
The rest are stored in the warehouse.
There are also 50 kg of gold and
10,000 taels of silver in the warehouse.
Look at this, Your Highness.
This is a golden dangling hairpin
adorned with twin blossoms.
And this one,
a gold-threaded butterfly
hairpin with a dangling pearl.
How exquisite.
Lately,
I tried everything I could,
but those betrothal gifts had already
been registered the inventory.
No one could touch them
without His Majesty's decree.
And early this morning,
they were delivered to
the Duke of Wei's Manor.
There is also this,
a dragon-and-phoenix auspicious platter.
You can use it when you have
pastries in the future, Your Highness.
The Crown Prince sent so many gifts,
and each one was
chosen with the utmost care.
Tagara Incense?
What did you say, Your Highness?
My name is Hua Fuhai.
I came today
hoping to request the return
of the Immortal Vine, Your Highness.
The Embroidered Envoys
are handling a case.
Anyone who dares to interfere
will be executed without mercy.
I'm Vice Minister Cui
of the Court of Judicial Review.
I have been waiting here for you,
Your Highness,
to investigate the case of
the escaped slave, Ling Long.
In this world,
the richest, the best fighters,
and those with the brightest futures
all take orders from
the owner of this Tagara Incense.
I am quite different.
I have stayed away from the court
for years and am all by myself.
I am just a frail, unnoticed,
and idle Crown Prince.
He managed to silently
infiltrate the Emperor's
most disciplined and secretive forces,
and he can even stand as an enemy
against Xiao Changqing and his brother.
This person is unpredictable.
All of you may leave now.
I want to be alone for a while.
(East Palace)
The Tagara Incense blend
on this bracelet
is unique.
I have only ever
smelled it on one person.
So, it turns out
you are that Tagara Incense.
Youyou,
let me explain.
I am all ears.
When I was gathering the Immortal Vine,
I happened to save you.
That was our first meeting,
and there was no calculation involved.
Seeing your cold
detachment toward Prince Lie,
I was surprised.
The wisdom and composure you showed
when taking the Rouge Ledger
made me curious.
The way you saw
through my disguised identity
earned my admiration
and won my heart even more.
When the poison flared up
and I almost lost my life,
it was you who gave the Immortal Vine
without a second thought
to a stranger like me.
Before I knew it,
I had already fallen too deep.
Later, when I found out
I only had five years left to live,
I did think about giving up
on this relationship.
But when I saw you fall off the cliff,
I suddenly realized
that I had already reached
a point where I couldn't let you go.
So, during that period of time,
you told me you
were leaving the capital,
but you actually went to the snowy peaks
to search for
the Extreme Frost Cordyceps.
And it was because of this
that the poison
blinded your eyes to colors.
Yes.
You play the part
of a frail Crown Prince,
yet you have been quietly
recruiting forces
and laying your trap in court,
all just to find
the person who poisoned you.
That person is hidden so deeply
that even now,
there is not a single clue.
That is why I never
made things clear to you.
Thank you for coming to my aid
time and again, Your Highness.
I will do everything I can to repay you.
But I ask Your Highness to cooperate
and break off our engagement.
What did you say?
Not only did you infiltrate
the Embroidered Envoys,
but you can also command
the wealthy Hua Fuhai.
Even Cui Jinbai,
the young and powerful minister
His Majesty trusts most,
is actually your subordinate.
You have never been
some innocent, harmless,
and weak Crown Prince.
If we turn against each other one day,
and I take a single misstep,
I will be utterly destroyed,
and it would even drag the Shen family
into eternal damnation.
If I had looked at
the betrothal gift list earlier,
there wouldn't have
been a marriage decree at all.
You weighed the pros and cons
and considered everything,
yet you failed to consider me.
In the end, you never believed
in my true feelings for you.
What do true feelings matter?
How many true feelings
change in an instant
when faced with conflicts of power?
I cannot do this at the expense
of my loved ones,
nor can I risk everything
to gamble on a heart
staying true forever.
(Sea Within the Heart)
Before the Grand Historian
sets the wedding date,
please think it over carefully,
Your Highness.
♪Let it all go,
give my tears to the flowers♪
♪Beneath my feet, eternal doom
is more than wind and sand♪
I will never allow you,
while I am still alive,
to marry anyone else.
♪Hides in the clamor♪
Any man of the imperial family
is mine to choose.
Even in front of His Majesty,
I would dare to say these words.
♪I want destiny,
and also tender words of love♪
♪As night stains my eyes,
I'll gaze once more at the rosy clouds♪
It doesn't matter what choice you make.
In the end,
you can only choose me.
♪In this eternity, you are a part of it♪
♪My longing can level mountains
and cross countless rivers♪
♪Drunk or sober, it's all like a dream♪
♪Stars sink into my hair,
the moon slips through my fingers♪
♪For how much joy
do we share this life together♪
♪Withering and flourishing,
year after year♪
I will take my leave.
♪A heart weathered by frost
will melt in love♪
♪Across countless miles
of treasured moments♪
♪With this broken body,
I'll become your armor♪
♪I want destiny,
and also tender words of love♪
♪As night stains my eyes,
I'll gaze once more at the rosy clouds♪
♪I have a dream
of a long wind in my sleeves♪
♪My heart rises and falls,
we embrace in a sea of clouds♪
♪In this eternity, you are a part of it♪
♪My longing can level mountains
and cross countless rivers♪
♪Drunk or sober, it's all like a dream♪
♪Stars sink into my hair,
the moon slips through my fingers♪
Commandery Princess,
how did your talk with
the Crown Prince go?
I want to part with him on good terms.
Right now, I only regret
that I shouldn't have
provoked him in the first place.
Before, I only thought
the Crown Prince was deep.
Only now do I realize
his abilities are so terrifying.
If he holds a grudge over
you calling off the wedding
and becomes our enemy,
what should we do, Your Highness?
If it's a fair and square battle,
win or lose,
I will accept the outcome.
I just don't want to
deal with him hypocritically,
and I don't want us to become the people
who guard against each other the most.
Commandery Princess,
do you really not plan
to marry into the East Palace?
No, I don't.
♪May the sand and dirt in my sleeves♪
(East Palace)
Who else
is a better match for you than me,
who has a legitimate imperial descent
and a short life expectancy?
Legitimate imperial descent
can be changed.
Whether your life is short or not
can be orchestrated.
Get out.
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
(No animals were harmed
in the making of this film)